原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Reginamoon 油炸电风扇 JohnnyG 一点都不酷喵 Giggles 木浅薰
翻译：杨一勾 Alex Lynn_宁   校对：杨一勾 木浅薰
时间轴：霜露   壬虚浪影  知之
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第十六集
最新海外影视剧下载
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
帕默发现我们在跟赛德尔合作了
Palmer figured out that we're doing this with Seidel.
除非我们撤诉
And unless we drop the lawsuit,
否则他要告我们合谋
he's gonna come after us for collusion.
如果我通过听证  帕默就动不了我们
If I pull out of that hearing, Palmer can't touch us.
但如果你不告诉纳森到底发生了什么的话
I'm not doing anything until
我什么也不做了
you tell Nathan exactly what's going on.
没什么好说的了
There's nothing to tell.
你说你接这个案子是为了重新当律师
You said you're doing this case as a way to get into the Bar.
我刚刚撤回了我的申请
And I just withdrew my application.
迈克被捕前我就知道他的诈骗行为
I knew Mike was a fraud before he was arrested.
还利用这事当上了冠名合伙人
I leveraged it to get my name on the wall.
我以为至少我知道你的为人
I thought I knew what kind of man you were.
你怎么敢这么说我
How dare you say that to me
我们第一次上床时
when the first time we slept together,
你还跟别人好着呢
you were with another man.
我不愿意和一个放弃了梦想的人
I don't want to spend the rest of my life
过一辈子
with a man who gave up on his dreams,
而且我知道你也不愿意当那个人
and I know that you don't want to be that man either.
我们有证据能证明超过一打的
We have proof of over a dozen instances
商业间谍行为
of you committing corporate espionage.
你们想要什么
What do you want?
跟那些矿工和解
You're gonna settle with those miners.
忘记听说过我们的事
You're gonna forget you ever heard of us.
并且继续诚实履行跟克雷格・塞德尔
And you're gonna honor your original agreement
原本达成的协议
with Craig Seidel.
我不仅想让你敲定听证
I don't just want you to set that hearing.
还想让你帮我清除掉所有拦路的人
I want you to bulldoze anyone who stands in my way.
几点了
What time is it?
别担心  你上班没迟到
Don't worry. You're not late for work.
-给  -谢谢
- Here. - Thanks.
我真需要这个
I could use this.
昨晚很晚才回来
I got in pretty late last night.
那跟我刚在厨房里发现的花
Does that have anything to do with the flowers
有关吗
I just found in the kitchen?
我就不能单纯因为爱你而给你买花吗
Can't a guy just buy you flowers 'cause he loves you?
是能  但不是这样的
He can. But he didn't.
你说对了
You're right.
我买花是为了感谢你
I bought them to say thank you
不惜一切来确保
for doing whatever it took to make sure
我能有机会成为律师
I got my shot at getting into the Bar.
等等  那么说
Wait, does that mean that...
是啊  我们做到了
Yeah. We did it.
我的听证会就在明天  赛德尔站在我们这边
My hearing's tomorrow. Seidel's on our side.
难以置信
I can't believe it.
这可能成真了
This could really happen.
是啊
I know.
怎么了
What is it?
我答应奥利佛会告诉纳森
I promised Oliver that I would tell Nathan
整件事的来龙去脉
about the whole thing.
-迈克  你不能那么做  -我知道
- Mike, you can't do that. - I know I can't.
但我得为听证会请几天的假
But I gotta get a couple days off for the hearing,
那么我总得给他个交待
which means I gotta tell him something.
路易  你来做什么
Louis, what are you doing here?
希望你不介意我过来
I hope you don't mind I stopped by.
我必须见你
I had to see you.
我昨晚一夜睡不着
I couldn't sleep at all last night.
-我也是  -塔拉  求你
- Neither could I. - Tara, please.
我知道我们吵架了
I know we had a fight,
但你说你想了解我
but you told me you wanted to get to know me.
我发誓  我告诉你的
And I swear, what I told you
是我做过的最坏的事
was the worst thing I've ever done.
路易  我难以接受的
Louis, the thing I'm having trouble dealing with
跟你们公司那个人的事无关
has nothing to do with that person at your firm.
而是你昨晚对我的态度
It has to do with how you treated me last night.
-塔拉  求你  -让我说完
- Tara, please. - Let me finish.
你对我说了很吓人的事
You shared something horrible with me,
又没给我时间接受
gave me no time to process it,
然后我还在消化这事的时候
and while I was taking it in,
你不仅攻击了我的人品
you not only attacked my integrity,
还让我为自己感到羞耻
you made me feel ashamed of myself.
你是对的
You're right.
我发火了  我不该的
I lashed out, and I shouldn't have.
但我那么做是因为担心你跟我分手
But I only did it because I was afraid of you rejecting me.
我...
And I will...
塔拉  如果你跟我分手我会死的
Tara, I'll die if you reject me.
问题就在这里  路易
That's the thing, Louis.
你是有理由做出那样的反应
You had a reason for reacting the way you did.
但我不确定我想跟一个
But I'm not sure I want to be with a man
认为他有任何理由那么对待我的男人在一起
who thinks there's ever a reason to treat me that way.
-塔拉  -对不起  路易
- Tara... - I'm sorry, Louis.
他们还在会议室等我呢
They're waiting for me in the conference room.
我说过我会打给你
I told you I'll call,
我会的
and I will call.
-纳森  -迈克  怎么了
- Nathan. - Mike. What's up?
没事  就想给你这个
Nothing. I just wanted to give you this.
这是五万美金的支票
This is a check for $50,000.
是啊  我们和解了
I know. We settled.
我昨晚把支票都给矿工了
I gave the miners their checks last night.
迈克  我们一个案子从未赚过这么多钱
Mike, this is the most money we've ever made on a case.
我们终于不用担心交不起房租了
For once, we're not gonna have to worry about making rent.
是啊
Yeah. Right.
我不是说笑
That's not a joke.
等等  你是说五万美金
Wait, you're telling me that $50,000
对于诊所会那么重要吗
can really make that big a difference to the clinic?
我是说  我知道在公司法里
I'm telling you that I know in corporate law,
钱都是按百万算的
money doesn't matter unless it's in the millions, but...
但在这里  五万美金就是天文数字了
here, $50,000 makes all the difference in the world.
那样的话  纳森  我从来这儿工作
Well, in that case, Nathan, I've been working here
就一直没休息过
seven days a week since I started,
我有私事要去处理
and I've got some personal stuff that I need to--
打住  你刚给我拿到了30天的租金
Stop right there. Look. You just bought me 30 days rent.
让你放几天假也是应该的
The least I can do is give you a few days back.
太好了  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-好了  说吧  -说什么
- Okay, let's hear it. - Hear what?
你想了一早上的段子
The joke you spent all morning coming up with.
什么段子
What joke?
我刚想问你法律图书馆怎么样
I was just gonna ask you where the law library was,
但随即意识到你从未去过
but then I realized you've never set foot in there.
你难道不该在诊所里拯救鲸鱼吗
Shouldn't you be at the clinic saving whales?
首先  那是绿色和平的事
First of all, that's Greenpeace.
其次  我请了假
And second of all, I took the day off
好准备应付品行考核委员会
so I could prepare for the Character and Fitness Committee.
那么你是要严肃对待
Oh, that means you're taking
不管会发生的什么岔子了
whatever that hitch is gonna be seriously.
-当然了  -这就对了
- You know I am. - That's what I like to hear.
因为我不希望在这里工作的人
Because I don't want somebody working here
不听取我的建议
who doesn't listen to my advice.
哈维  我觉得你还是不明白
Harvey, I still don't think you understand.
等这事结束  我不会回来的
When this thing is over, I am not coming back here.
-迈克  -我说过  我想做好事
- Mike-- - I told you, I want to do good.
-那就在这儿做好事  -我还说过
- Then do good here. - And I also told you
我当初之所以答应了这件事
that the only reason I agreed to this whole thing in the first place
是因为我不忍心
was because I couldn't stand
看奥利佛那样的人失败
to watch someone like Oliver fail
而又无法帮助他
and not be able to help him.
而奥利佛那类人又不在这样的地方工作
and people like Oliver don't work in places like this.
他们在那样的地方工作
They work in places like that.
而你这类人不应该被允许在任何地方工作
And people like you shouldn't be working anywhere.
你来这里干什么  安妮塔
What are you doing here, Anita?
我来这里是因为联邦检察官办公室要求
I'm here because the U.S. Attorney's Office requested that
一旦迈克・罗斯申请要成为律师  必须通知他们
they be notified if Mike Ross ever applied to the Bar.
联邦检察官办公室和迈克有什么关系
What does the U.S. Attorney's Office have to do with Mike?
没关系  只是我碰巧在那里工作而已
Nothing. Except I happen to work there.
而且一周以前
And as of one week ago,
我还成为了品行考核委员会的新成员
I'm also the newest member of the Character and Fitness Committee.
放屁
Bullshit.
要走完一整套程序才能加入那个委员会
There's a whole process to get on that committee.
你不可能正好在走那个程序
There's no way you just happened to be in the pipeline.
没错  我的确没有
You're right. I wasn't.
但一旦有成员卸任
But when a member takes leave,
他有权任命他的接班人
he has the right to appoint his replacement.
而沃特・山姆森委任了我
And Walter Samson appointed me.
你以为我不会挖出
You think I'm not gonna find out
你是动了什么手脚才让这人让位的吗
whatever bullshit you did to get this guy to drop out?
随便挖
Be my guest,
因为假如迈克要去参加那个听证会
because if Mike is going before that hearing,
那意味着你一定也动了手脚
that means you did something too.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我想告诉你  你可以取消这次听证
I want to tell you you might as well cancel this hearing,
为我们大家都节省许多时间
save us all a lot of time.
因为必须全票通过才算通过
Because the vote has to be unanimous.
而我绝对不会投通过的
And you are never getting my vote.
诉讼双雄
第六季第十六集[季终]
瑞秋  无论你在做什么  都得先放一放
Rachel, whatever you're doing, you need to put it down
然后开始找在没有全票通过的情况下
and start looking for every single instance
一个人依然获得了律师资格的案例
where a person was admitted to the Bar and the vote wasn't unanimous.
迈克  出什么事了
Mike, what's going on?
安妮塔・吉布斯加入了委员会
Anita Gibbs got herself onto the board.
那我们该做的是找个办法把她踢出去
Then what we should be doing is finding a way to get her kicked off.
哈维在想办法了  但与此同时
Harvey's working on it. But in the meantime,
我需要了解关于这个委员会的一切细节
I need to know the ins and outs of this committee,
因为只要她还在委员会里
because while she's on it,
她就会用尽一切肮脏的手段
she's gonna use every dirty trick in the book
试图把这件事直接扼杀在摇篮里的
to end this thing before it gets started.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要窝在图书馆里
I'm gonna go hole myself up in the library
为回答每一个我能想到的肮脏问题做准备
and start preparing answers to every dirty question i can think of.
路易  你还好吗
Louis, are you okay?
我没事  唐娜
I'm fine, Donna.
有什么需要我帮忙的吗
What can I do for you?
我知道你知道本杰明和我正在创业
I know you know Benjamin and I have been working on a business.
但我不确定你是否知道
But I'm not sure that you know
我们找了斯图做投资人
that we brought on Stu as an investor.
我不知道  唐娜  那真是太棒了
I didn't, Donna; That's great.
的确
It is.
但出了个问题  而我需要你的帮助
But there's a problem, and I need your help with it.
你尽管开口
Anything.
本杰明去申请了专利
Benjamin applied for a patent,
但发现我们的技术和另一个人的重合了
and it turns out that our technology overlaps with someone else's.
-重合度有多高  -32.5%
- How much overlap? - 32.5%.
超过最高限度了
That's over the threshold.
除非本杰明能把重合度降到30...
Unless Benjamin can get you below 30--
他做不到
He can't.
但斯图说我们可以和那个专利持有人协商
But Stu says we can negotiate with whoever holds the patent,
让他们授权给我们
get them to give us an exclusion,
那我们就可以继续推进真・唐娜这个项目了
and we'll still be able to move forward with The Donna.
唐娜  我正需要这个
Donna, this is exactly what I need.
什么意思
What do you mean?
塔拉和我大吵了一架
Tara and I got into a huge fight.
她如今正在决定我们还要不要继续
She's deciding right now if we're gonna stay together.
我正需要做点什么来转移注意力
This is exactly what I needed to take my mind off it.
路易  我不想让自己听起来不近人情
Louis, I don't mean to sound insensitive,
但这事对我真的很重要
but this is incredibly important to me.
我了解你
I know you,
假如你的状态会让你把这件事搞砸
and if this is gonna make you go in there and blow this thing up,
那可不行
I can't have that.
唐娜  听我说
Donna, listen to me.
我也许会失去我生命中最亲近的女人
I may be losing the closest woman in my life,
但你是第二亲近的
but you are the second closest.
我发誓我不会做任何危害你的公司的事
I swear that I won't do anything to harm your company.
谢谢  加油
Thank you. Knock ’em dead.
你什么时候才打算告诉我
When were you gonna tell me?
告诉你什么
Tell you what?
那个把迈克送进监狱的检察官
That the prosecutor that put Mike in prison
把自己弄进了委员会
just got herself put on that panel.
-什么  -没错
- What? - That's right.
而我想知道我为什么没有从你这里听说这件事
And I want to know why I heard about it from her and not you.
我告诉你为什么  因为我不知道
I'll tell you why. Because I didn't know.
但如今我知道了  这件事玩完了
But now that I do, this thing is done.
-玩完个屁  -你疯了吗
- The hell it is. - Are you crazy?
安妮塔・吉布斯可是助理联邦检察官
Anita Gibbs is a goddamn Assistant U.S. Attorney.
一旦她发现了一丁点迹象
She gets one whiff of this,
我俩都会被吊销律师执照的
and we are both disbarred.
所以我们要把她踢出委员会
Which is why we're gonna make sure that doesn't happen
以确保这件事不会发生
by getting her kicked off that panel.
我们要怎样才能做到那一点
And how exactly are we gonna do that?
你先把所有我需要知道的
We're gonna start by you telling me
关于沃特・山姆森的事  仔仔细细地告诉我
everything there is to know about Walter Samson.
那我们现在一样也可以放弃了
Well, then we might as well give up right now,
因为沃特・山姆森干净得像婴儿
because Walter Samson is as clean as they come.
-没人有那么清白  -这个人就是
- No one is that clean. - Well, this guy is.
-而且我没有...  -听我说
- And I didn't sign on-- - Listen to me.
你说过你加入的
You said you were in on this.
我现在告诉你  你依旧是我们这条船上的
And I'm telling you right now, you still are.
因为我们千方百计地帮你摆脱了麻烦
Because we moved heaven and earth to get you out of hot water,
我可不介意把你重新打入地狱
and I got no problem putting you right back in.
好
Fine.
但你最好小心一点
But you better be careful.
因为如果你想调查吉布斯
Because if you're looking at Gibbs,
她也会调查我们
she's going to be looking at us.
而你大白天来我的大堂找我
And you coming to my lobby in the middle of the day
就会让她抓住把柄
is going to get us all caught.
先生们  虽然是临时通知
Gentlemen, thank you for meeting with me
-感谢你们愿意见我  -不客气
- on such short notice. - Our pleasure.
我想你们应该已经看过我发给你们的文件了
I assume you looked through the documents I sent over
合二位心意吗
and found them to your liking?
正相反  我们感到非常不爽
On the contrary, we found them most disturbing.
具体地说  你们是使用了
In particular, the fact that you used
我们的基本原则才能够完成设计
our fundamental principles and worked up from there.
什么
What?
我们在申请专利前
We've never even seen your fundamental principles
从未看过你们的基本原则
prior to applying for that patent.
你能证明吗
Can you prove that?
当然没法证明
Of course we can't... prove that.
没法证明没看过
It's not possible to prove a negative.
每个将别人的技术
Words spoken by every hack who's ever copied
窃为己有的人都会这么说
someone else's technology and claimed it as their own.
什么情况
What's going on here?
我诚心诚意地来谈授权
I came to you to negotiate an exclusion in good faith.
我们计划报价
And we're prepared to offer you--
我们不关心你们的报价
We don't care what you're prepared to offer.
我们让你来也不是要给你提供授权
And we didn't bring you here to give you an exclusion.
而是要借你传达个消息
We brought you here to send a message.
这是起诉你委托人的文件  要求赔偿九千万
This is a $90 million lawsuit against your client
如果他们让产品上市的话
if they go to market.
二位  别这样
Gentlemen, please,
我不是说我们先发明的
I am not saying we got here first.
但只是超过了2.5%
But it's a 2.5% overlap,
而我们愿意支付15%的收益分成
and we are open to a 15% revenue sharing arrangement.
我们根本不在乎  因为是我们在先
And we're not open to shit, because we were here first.
听好了  我在尽量克制了
Listen to me. I am trying to keep my cool.
我们不管你能否克制
We don't care if you keep your cool or not.
因为我们抓住你了
Because we've got you,
而你却无能为力
and there's nothing you can do about it.
你可以把你的报价塞进抽屉里了
So you can take your offer and shove it in a drawer
还有那个破烂电子秘书
along with that sorry excuse for a digital secretary,
因为两者没有一个能见天日
because neither one of them is ever gonna see the light of day.
奥利佛  你干什么呢
Oliver. What are you doing?
还有效吗
Is it still on?
-什么还有效吗  -你的交易
- Is what still on? - Your deal.
成为律师
To get into the Bar.
奥利佛  听我说
Oliver, listen to me.
因为当我问纳森你去哪儿了
Because when I asked Nathan where you were,
他说你要请几天假处理私事
he said you were taking a couple days for personal reasons.
突然之间
And all of a sudden,
我就感到挥之不去的恶心
I got this pit in my stomach that wouldn't go away.
于是我决定来问问你我是否有理由恶心
So I decided to ask you if there's a reason I got that pit
或者我只不过是个怀疑你的混蛋
or if I'm just an asshole for doubting you.
你不是混蛋  奥利佛
You're not an asshole, Oliver.
该死的  迈克
God damn it, Mike!
你跟我说过  你不会告诉纳森
You told me you didn't have to tell Nathan
因为无事可说
because there was nothing to tell.
我和你说的时候的确是那样
And when I told you that, there wasn't.
后来我的交易又回到了桌面上
But then my deal got put back on the table.
也就是说今天早上你本可以告诉他
Which means you could have told him this morning.
而你没有  现在我得去说了
But you didn't, so now I have to.
奥利佛  等等  拜托听我说
Oliver, hey, wait! Please, hear me out!
我才不听你说  迈克
I'm not gonna hear you out, Mike.
我在这里等了你一个小时
I was sitting here for an hour,
希望是我看错你了
hoping I was wrong about you.
你没看错我
You weren't wrong about me.
我在乎人们  我希望能帮助诊所
I care about people. I want to help the clinic.
我之所以没告诉纳森
And the reason I didn't tell Nathan what I did
是因为我想等我有能力帮他更多的时候再说
is because I'm just waiting until I can help him even more.
怎么帮  做一个见不得人的律师吗
Help how? By being a shady lawyer?
做一个不会让索菲亚・普莱斯丢掉房子的人
By being someone who wouldn't have lost Sofia Price her home.
真不相信你会说出这句话
I cannot believe you just said that to me.
因为这是事实  你也清楚
I said it because it's true, and you know it.
我的听证会一结束
Look, I am gonna tell Nathan everything
我就马上把事情都告诉纳森  我向你保证
as soon as my hearing is over. You have my word.
我凭什么要相信骗子的话
Why should I believe the word of a liar?
就凭我为那些矿工和诊所所做的事情
Because of what I did for those miners and the clinic.
如果这些还不够  我为你做的可以吗
And if that's not enough, how about what I did for you?
你屁都没为我做  但我不会告诉纳森
You didn't do shit for me. But fine, I won't tell Nathan.
只要这件事情一结束
Just so long as when this thing's over,
你就滚回你的狗屁商业界
you go back to your corrupt corporate world.
因为不管你告诉自己什么
Because I don't care what you tell yourself.
你都不属于我的世界
You're never gonna belong in mine.
哈维  还在这儿干什么
Harvey, what are you still doing here?
听证会在城市对角  十分钟就开始了
The hearing's across town in ten minutes.
我不去听证会了  唐娜  你也不要去
I'm not going to the hearing, Donna, and neither are you.
-为什么  -因为如果我们俩做不到该做的事
- Why not? - Because if you and I can't do
不管迈克在听证会上怎么表现
what we need to, then whatever Mike does at that hearing
-都无所谓了  -告诉我
- isn't gonna matter. - Give it to me.
我们得找到沃特・山姆森的弱点
We need to figure out what Walter Samson's weak spot is.
告诉我该怎么做  我全力以赴
Tell me how, and I'm all in.
从联系所有认识他的人
Start by contacting every person we know
问问他们知道这个混蛋有什么事情开始
and asking them what they know about this asshole.
因为吉布斯握有他的把柄
Because Gibbs has something on him
如果我找不出来
and if I can't find out what it is,
我就没法把她踢出委员会
then I can't get her off that committee.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去见一个根本不认识山姆森的人
To see someone who doesn't know Samson at all.
在开始之前  我要指出
Before we get started, I'd like to point out
此类访谈通常是为了我们快速批准
these interviews are normally for us to quickly approve
标准申请人进入律师协会
standard applicants to the Bar.
但是  罗斯先生并非完全符合申请人标准
However, Mr. Ross is no standard applicant.
所以  我们将不对他的审核环节限时
Therefore, we will convene for as long as it takes
直到得出判定结果
before ruling on his application.
-现在  -主席先生  请允许我发言
- Now... - Mr. Chairman, if I may.
去年冬天  罗斯先生认罪
Last winter, Mr. Ross pled guilty
承认其对纽约市民犯下了欺诈罪
to defrauding the citizens of New York.
所以  我提议立刻拒绝他的申请
Therefore, I propose we reject his application right now
因为罗斯先生是罪犯
because Mr. Ross is a felon
纽约律师协会不接受罪犯
and the New York Bar does not accept felons.
主席先生  我无意冒犯这位协会的新成员
Mr. Chairman, with all due respect to the new board member,
但有过接受先例的
you do.
而且协会不仅接受罪犯  多年前更是
Not only does the Bar accept felons, but years ago,
此协会认可了尼尔・维斯纳
this very committee admitted Neal Wiesner,
一个因谋杀未遂入狱多年的罪犯
a man who spent years in prison for attempted murder.
吉布斯小姐也许觉得我的罪行
Now, Ms. Gibbs may think my crime is worse
甚至比谋杀未遂更恶劣  但我不认为
than attempted murder, but I don't think
就恶劣到值得协会放弃140多年的先例
it's worth throwing away 140 years of precedent
甚至不给我一个为自己说话的机会
by not even allowing me to make my case.
加油  快快快
Come on, let's go!
加油啊  该死
Come on, shit.
你干什么呢
What the hell are you doing?
你看我像在干什么
What does it look like I'm doing?
眼睁睁看着我的钱打了水漂
I'm watching my money go down the toilet.
在我看来是我给了你一个任务
Well, it looks to me like I paid you to do a job,
你却坐在这里无所事事
and you're sitting here doing this.
好吧  我就告诉你一个小秘密
Okay, I'll let you in on a little secret.
电脑入侵只需要十五分钟
It only takes 15 minutes to hack someone.
接下来的45分钟里要是找不到有用的事
If you can't find something in the next 45,
就说明它根本不存在
it means there's nothing to find.
胡扯  肯定有什么的
Bullshit. There's always something to find.
我说实话  真没有
I'm telling you, there isn't.
他不碰烟酒不赌不偷  不沾坏事
He doesn't drink, smoke, gamble, cheat, nothing.
给我听好  我给了你一大笔钱搞定这事
Listen to me. I paid you good money to do a job,
如果你不给我认真点
and if you don't put some more effort into this,
我就会把你一无是处的事广而告之
I'm gonna spread the word that you aren't worth shit.
而这次不再是路易・利特没信誉的话
And this time it won't be coming from Louis Litt.
-而是我的  -那把你的臭钱拿走
- It'll be coming from me. - Then keep your damn money.
当我告诉你找不到什么的时候
When I tell you there's nothing to find,
就是真的不存在
there's nothing to find.
我的意思是我不仅承认我的所作所为
I guess what I'm saying is not only do I admit what I did,
而且  我很后悔
but... I regret it
诚心诚意的后悔
with every fiber of my being.
我愿意向我的委托人们
And I'd like to apologize to my clients,
向我的前同事们
my former colleagues,
向从我是个孩子起  就一直想
and finally to the fraternity of men and woman
加入的协会的兄弟姐妹们
that I've wanted to be a member of
真诚致歉
since I was a child.
真是感人的陈述
Well, that was a moving statement.
我就一个问题
I just have one question.
要是你这么后悔你的所作所为
If you regret what you did so much,
你为什么不愿意服满刑期
why weren't you willing to serve your full sentence?
我没有不愿意
Well, I wasn't unwilling.
有人提出交易  让我帮忙给某罪犯定罪
I was offered a deal to help convict a known criminal,
我就答应了
and I took it.
你是答应了一个能提前被释放的交易
You were offered a deal to get out early, and you took it.
我保护了一个无辜的人...
I protected an innocent man--
你所做的不过是渗入你室友的生活
What you did was insinuate yourself into your roommate's life,
获得他的信任
gain his trust,
假装自己是他的朋友  是否如此
and pretend to be his friend. True or false?
你这纯粹是断章取义
You're taking it out of context.
要说全部事实就是你说自己是一回事
The context is you portrayed yourself as one thing
而其实是另一回事
when, really, you were another,
而这正是你谎称自己是律师的
which is what you did the entire time
整个过程中干的
you pretended to be an attorney
也是我认为你现在正在做的事
and what I believe you are doing to this body right now.
主席先生
Mr. Chairmen,
如果她在他陈述中就对他的人格进行抨击
if she's going to impugn his character while he's speaking,
那他就有权找人为他作证
then he's entitled to let someone else speak for him.
这不是庭审
This isn't a trial.
我们不允许品性证人发言
We don't allow character witnesses here.
事实上  协会允许
Actually, you do.
第四章16A款规定
Article 4, 16A.
申请人允许请证人出席
Applicants are allowed a witness as a rebuttal
反驳由协会成员提出的指控
for an accusation leveled by a committee member.
那条规定已经30年没用过了
That article hasn't been cited in 30 years.
也许是因为从来没有申请人被迫
Maybe that's because no applicant has ever had to stand
由送自己进监狱的人品评过
before the person who put them away.
有道理
You make a point.
我们明天一早听取你找到的
We'll pick this up first thing in the morning
证人的陈述  谢谢
with your witness. Thank you.
瑞秋  你的话帮了我大忙
Rachel, that was exactly what I needed.
-要不是你...  -我知道
- If you hadn't done that... - I know.
但现在我更担心的是
But right now I'm more concerned with the fact
她会让成员们讨厌你
that she's turning them against you.
也就是说即使哈维拉她下马
Which means even after Harvey kicks her off,
赛德尔要说服所有人也难上加难了
Seidel's job is gonna be that much harder.
而我们只有机会找一个人替我说话
And we only have one shot at having someone speak for me.
迈克  走吧  我们得赶紧回公司
Mike, come on. We gotta get back to the office
开始思考谁能做这件事
and start going through everyone it could be.
从正反两方面列个对比表格
We'll make a list of pros and cons.
瑞秋  我知道该找谁
Rachel... I know who it is.
朱利叶斯
Julius.
迈克  你怎么来了
Mike. What are you doing here?
我想找你谈谈
I was hoping we could talk.
抱歉  伙计  现在不方便
Look, I'm sorry, man. This is not a good time.
我刚把孩子哄睡着  我和妻子正...
I just put the baby down and the wife and I--
求你  不用很久的
Please, it won't take long.
明天我有场听证会
I got this hearing tomorrow
是律师协会的品行考核
for the Character portion of the Bar,
我想问你愿不愿意替我说话
and I wanted to ask if you'd speak for me.
你不介意我问下  为什么找我
You mind if I ask, why me?
因为你是我认识的人中唯一一个有资格
Because you're the only one I know who's qualified
告诉委员会我出来之后
to tell the board that I was a different man
已经不是以前那个人了
when I got out than when I went in.
无意冒犯  迈克
No offense, Mike...
但事实上  我不确定你是否改过自新了
but the truth is, I'm not sure you are.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说这个听证会在明天
I mean you said this hearing is tomorrow.
而你现在才来找我
But you're just now coming to me,
这意味着出了什么状况
which means something's going on.
状况就是把我抓起来的那个女人
What's going on is the woman who put me away
进入了听证委员会
managed to get herself on the committee,
而今她又当面挑衅我
and now she's slamming the door in my face.
-那她为什么要这么做  -朱利叶斯
- And why would she do that? - Julius--
迈克  你怎么会有听证会
Mike, how did you even get a hearing?
你说什么呢  我跟别人一样申请了
What are you talking about? I applied, like everyone else.
不  你跟别人不一样
No, you're not like everyone else.
-你都没上过法学院  -那不重要
- You didn't go to law school. - It doesn't matter.
有个例外叫"熟读法律"
There's an exception called "Reading the law."
发现了吗迈克  就这
See, right there, Mike,
听起来就像我在监狱里遇到的胡扯的骗子一样
that sounds like the bullshit artist I met in prison.
那你现在告诉我
So you tell me right now.
你是不是搞了什么事才弄到的听证会
Did you pull some shit to make this happen?
该死迈克  如果你不跟我坦白
Damn, Mike, if you can't be straight with me,
我就立马结束谈话
this conversation ends right here.
好吧  我承认
Yes, I did.
还是啊  夜幕下的真相
Finally. Some truth in the night.
朱利叶斯  我在一家法律诊所工作
Julius, I work at a law clinic,
但不是以律师身份
but not as a lawyer.
我曾有一个成为律师的机会摆在眼前
An opportunity presented itself for me to become one
而我拒绝了
and I turned it down,
然后我不得不坐在那
but then I had to sit there
眼睁睁看着一个女人因为我帮不上忙
and watch a woman get put on the street
而被赶到大街上
because I couldn't help her.
我知道我会一次又一次地
And I knew I'd have to watch that happen
看到这种情况
over and over and over.
所以当那个机会第二次出现时
So when that opportunity presented itself for the second time,
我抓住了
I took it.
因为我知道它如果消失就不会再来
Because I knew it would never come along again.
-你也不知道会怎么样  迈克  -我知道
- You don't know that, Mike. - I do know that.
所以你愿意的话可以拒绝
So you can say no if you want to,
但不能说我没有改变
but don't say I haven't changed.
因为你那晚在监狱遇到的迈克
Because the Mike you met that night in prison
永远不会像刚才那样对你说出真相
never would have told you the truth just now.
朱利叶斯  拜托了
Julius, please.
我需要这个机会
I need this.
这是地址
This is the address.
明早八点
It's tomorrow at 9:00.
我没有别人可找了
I don't have anyone else.
迈克
Mike, hey.
哈维  告诉我你有些好消息
Harvey, tell me you got some good news.
我确实有  我搞定了赛德尔
I do. I took care of Seidel.
他还是会支持你的
He's still gonna back you.
我不是说赛德尔
I'm not talking about Seidel.
我是说把吉布斯挤出委员会
I'm talking about getting Gibbs off that committee.
这事没那么容易
It's not that simple.
那有什么不容易的
What's not that simple about it?
我还没找到跟他有关的任何事
I haven't found anything on him yet.
哈维  我努力地赢得好感
Harvey, I am struggling to get someone on my side,
但只要她在委员会里
and every second that she is on that committee
就会说服人反感我
she is turning people against me.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
迈克  我跟你说过我来搞定
Mike, I told you I'd get it done.
我就一定会搞定的
I'll get it done.
-有什么收获  -没有
- Anything? - No.
和你一个小时前打电话时一样
It's the same as when you called an hour ago.
如果他杀了人去藏尸
If he killed someone and hid the body,
没有人知道会在哪
nobody knows where it is.
那你告诉我名单上下一个是谁
Then why don't you tell me who's next on the list.
哈维  我忙这个忙了一整天了
Harvey, I have been at this all day,
你说我们的时间所剩不多
and you said we don't have much time.
那你为什么不去忽悠那个家伙
Why don't you just bluff the guy
搞到你需要的东西
into giving you whatever you need?
因为这件事我们只有一次机会
Because we've only got one shot at this.
我掌握的信息越多
The more information I have,
我忽悠成功的可能性越大
the better chance a bluff is gonna work.
哈维  到底怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
这不像你的风格宁愿待在屋里打电话
It isn't like you to stay in and make phone calls
也不去当面去会会别人
instead of confronting someone face-to-face.
要是我做不到
What if I can't do it
迈克不能成为律师呢
and Mike doesn't get into the Bar?
你怎么会这么说
How can you say that?
你是我见过最好的扑克玩家
You are the best poker player I have ever seen.
你能做到的
You can do it.
我觉得你不太明白  唐娜
I don't think you understand, Donna.
只有他不清白时忽悠才有用
A bluff only works if he's dirty.
要是这个家伙身家清白呢
What if the guy really is clean?
哈维  吉布斯把他从协会挤了出去
Harvey, Gibbs got him off the committee.
他并不清白
He's not clean.
别再说丧气话了
Now, enough is enough.
该做什么做什么去
Go do what you do.
路易  你介意说下这是什么吗
Louis, you mind telling me what this is?
你从哪弄来的
Where'd you get that?
那是针对唐娜新生意的诉讼
That is a lawsuit against Donna's new business.
我知道那是什么
I know what it is.
那你为什么还不告诉她
Well, why haven't you told her about it yet?
因为她会认为我是因为塔拉的事心烦
Because she's gonna think that I blew it
而搞砸了这件事
because I was upset about Tara.
路易  你是不是冲哪个小可怜撒气了
Louis, did you go full-blown you on some poor bastard
而搞砸了唐娜成功的机会
and ruin Donna's chance at success?
格蕾琴  我是满怀诚意的去和解的
Gretchen, I went there in good faith to get a settlement,
是他们不友好
and I was ambushed.
-我发誓  -那你去把它处理好
- I swear. - Then you need to fix it.
-我不能  -为什么不能
- I can't. - Why not?
因为我没有办法不想塔拉
Because I cannot stop thinking about Tara.
我们大吵了一架
We got into a huge fight
我真是个  混蛋
and I was... such an asshole.
所以我去道歉
So I went to apologize.
她说她不确定她还能不能和我在一起
She said she wasn't sure she could stay with me,
从那以后我就没了她的消息
and I haven't heard from her since.
所以现在不止是生活中一个女人的事
So now instead of not knowing how to fix things
我解决不了
with one woman in my life,
而且另一个女人的事我也无法解决
I don't know how to fix things with the other.
路易  我之前有段很长的婚姻
Louis, I was married a long time.
我要告诉你  卡尔和我是有分歧的
And I'll tell you, Carl and I had some doozies.
老实告诉你
Tell you the truth,
不是每次我都确信我们能度过的
I wasn't always sure we were gonna pull through.
但我们都度过了  因为我们彼此相爱
But we always did, because we loved each other.
如果她不再爱我了怎么办
What if she doesn't love me anymore?
爱不是那么容易消逝的  路易
It doesn't turn off like that, Louis.
而且从我的角度来看
And from where I'm standing,
你值得被爱
you're worth loving.
现在  你觉得你能解决这件事
Now, do you think you can fix this thing
还是说你需要我给咱们找个帮手
or do you need me to get us some help?
我不需要帮助
I don't need any help.
我要把这些家伙打的屁滚尿流
I'm gonna blow those guys out of the water.
-沃特・山姆森  -没错
- Walter Samson? - Yes?
我在外面看见你了  第一次来玩吗
I saw you out there. First time playing?
抱歉  我认识你吗
Sorry. Do I know you?
问题是  你是怎么认识安妮塔・吉布斯的
The question is, how do you know Anita Gibbs?
因为你把你在
Because you gave her your seat
律师品行委员会的位置给了她
on the Character and Fitness Committee,
而这个起诉迈克・罗斯的女人
and the woman who prosecuted Mike Ross
没有资格得到它
has no business being there.
-迈克・罗斯是谁  -我理解
- Who's Mike Ross? - I get it.
我们要这样玩  是吗
We're going that way, huh?
他就是吉布斯强迫你放弃
He's the reason Gibbs strong-armed you
你位置的原因
into giving up that seat.
我放弃这个位置
I gave up that seat
-是因为我想花时间多陪陪家人  -瞎扯
- because I wanted to spend more time with my family. - Bullshit.
她发现了你不可告人的肮脏小秘密
She found out whatever dirty little secret you're hiding.
如果你不向我坦白
If you don't come clean with me,
我会去查清楚是什么  我的威胁会更甚
I'm gonna find out what it is and I'm gonna squeeze harder.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are,
但生活在一个人人都有弱点
but it must be nice living in a world
以及不道德行为的世界  感觉一定很好
where everyone has a weak spot and is unethical,
但现在的情况是
but in this case,
我选择了离职
I took a leave of absence
选了一个配得上的律师替代我
and I replaced myself with a worthy attorney.
所以你随便去找我的弱点
So you can look for a pressure point all you want.
但我很遗憾的告诉你
But I'm sorry to inform you,
你什么也找不到的
you're not gonna find one.
你想知道我是谁  我是哈维・斯佩克特
You want to know who I am? My name is Harvey Specter.
你可以说你从没听过迈克・罗斯
And you can say you never heard of Mike Ross,
但我知道你听说过我
but I know you heard of me.
所以也许她没对你进行勒索
So maybe she didn't blackmail you.
也许她对你许下了什么承诺
Maybe she promised to do something for you.
不管是什么  我都会查清楚是什么
Either way, I'm gonna find out what it is
而那时你会希望你现在就告诉了我一切
and you're gonna wish you told me right now.
你以为你是在向我示威
You think you're showing strength.
但恐吓只代表软弱
But intimidation is only weakness.
顺便告诉你
And for your information,
在任命安妮塔・吉布斯
I never met Anita Gibbs
接替我的位置前  我从没见过她
until the day I appointed her as my replacement.
当我第一次见到迈克・罗斯时
When I first met Mike Ross,
我以为他和我之前见过的其他罪犯一样
I thought he was like every other criminal I work with:
一个想不劳而获的诈骗犯
an entitled fraud who spent his life cutting corners.
但我来是为了告诉你们  他已经不是
But I'm here to tell you, he went into prison one man,
进监狱时的那个他了
and he walked out another.
从我的专业角度看
And in my professional opinion,
他拥有能作为律师服务于社会的诚信
he has the integrity to serve his community as a lawyer.
我不怀疑您是出于真心  罗威先生
While I don't doubt your sincerity, Mr. Rowe,
但仅仅因为他骗到了你
just because he was able to fool you
不代表他就能骗过委员会
doesn't mean he's going to be able to fool this board.
是罗威医生
It's Dr. Rowe.
我很高兴回应我陈述的人是您
And I'm glad you were the one who responded to my statement.
为什么
And why is that?
因为之前是你试图对他的释放做出误读
Because you tried to paint a false picture of his release,
而我正是来拨乱反正的
and I'm here to set the record straight.
我没有误读
The record is straight.
而且你没资格讨论他之前的交易
And you're not qualified to talk about the deal that he made.
-不  我们想听听  -谢谢
- No, we're gonna hear this. - Thank you.
罗斯先生之前达成提前释放协议这不假
It's true Mr. Ross entered into an early release agreement.
但他为了狱友的安全延迟了自己的释放
But it's also true that he stayed in longer than he had to
也是事实
to keep his cellmate safe.
当他在里面时  他冒着生命危险
And while he was there, he risked his own life
阻止了一个暴力的罪犯骗得假释
to prevent a violent man from falsely obtaining parole.
说不定
And for all we know,
他这么做是出于私心
he did that for self-serving reasons.
在我看来  你现在做的事才是出于私心
And for all I know, that's what you're doing right now.
你过分了
You're out of line.
现在接受审查的人不是我
I'm not the one under examination here.
也不是我  我是一名监狱的心理医生
Neither am I. I'm a prison psychologist.
根据我的经验
And in my experience,
有私心的男人不会冒着生命危险帮助他人
self-serving men do not risk their lives to help people.
我不觉得欺骗自己的朋友是帮助他人
I don't call defrauding your fellow man helping people.
更不会认为这叫诚信
And I certainly don't call it having integrity.
恕我直言  女士
With all due respect, ma'am,
我不想和你浪费口舌
I'm done wasting my breath on you
因为这个听证会的目的是非常明确的
because the purpose of this hearing was to determine
那就是迈克・罗斯是否已经改正
if Mike Ross had reformed.
但你似乎对那并不感兴趣
But you don't seem to be interested in that
因为你已经做出了判断
because you've already made your mind up.
也许是的
Maybe I have.
那么也许是你没有资格进入委员会
Then maybe you shouldn't be on this committee.
如我所说  以我的专业观点
Because as I said, in my professional opinion,
世界需要迈克・罗斯这样的律师
the world could use a lawyer like Mike Ross.
如果你问我的个人意见
And if you're looking for my personal opinion,
你所拥有的正直
he has more integrity in his little finger
不及他的万分之一
than you have in your whole body.
哈维  你去哪了
Harvey, where have you been?
想办法替我们挽回局势
I've been trying to level the playing field.
我说的就是这个  我们已经做到了
That's the thing; we just did.
你真应该看看朱利叶斯在那的表现
You should have seen Julius up there.
如果成员们听了他的话
I mean, if those members vote no
居然还会投反对票...
after hearing what he had to say--
他说了什么都无关紧要
Doesn't matter what he had to say.
你还没有找到把吉布斯踢出委员会的办法
You haven't found a way to get Gibbs off that committee.
没有
No.
抱歉  迈克
I'm sorry, Mike.
你不用抱歉  哈维
You don't have to be sorry, Harvey.
她警告过我们她不会让我当成律师的
She warned us that she'd never let me into the Bar.
我们只是没有相信
We just didn't listen.
听我说
Listen to me.
明天早上才投票
This vote isn't until tomorrow morning.
我们还有时间想想办法
There's still time for us to think of something.
你继续想办法吧  哈维
You keep trying, Harvey.
我还有别的事得处理一下
I got something else I need to take care of.
怎么了
What's going on?
格蕾琴说你想和我聊聊专利的事
Gretchen said you wanted to talk to me about the patent.
你们怎么来了
What are you guys doing here?
我回去找他们了  唐娜
I went back to them, Donna.
我把斯图和本杰明叫来是因为我想让你知道
And the reason I asked Stu and Benjamin to be here
不是我搞砸了这件事
was so that you'd know I didn't shit the bed.
你是说你没能让他们做出让步吗
Are you telling me you couldn't get them to back off the lawsuit?
他是说我们不能给真・唐娜申请专利
He's telling you we won't be able to patent The Donna at all.
-什么  -唐娜
- What? - Donna.
他们不授权让我们和他们合作
They weren't authorized to let us partner with them.
那正是我让你处理的事
That's what I sent you over there to take care of.
我知道  他们说他们会和我们
I know, and then they said they would fight us
把官司打到底的
to the ends of the earth.
所以我想尽办法
So I pulled out every trick in the book.
让他们提了条件
And I got them to make you an offer.
听起来像是买断
An offer sounds like a buyout.
因为就是买断
That's because it is a buyout.
用一项特别条款  允许我们
With a special provision that allows us
生产真・唐娜做内部使用
to produce The Donna for in-house use.
那不够好
That's not good enough.
唐娜  他们愿意付一大笔钱
Donna, we're talking about a lot of money.
我并不在乎钱  斯图
I don't care about the money, Stu.
我在乎的是路易没有为我而战
I care that Louis didn't fight for me.
我为你斗争了  唐娜  我发誓
I did fight for you, Donna, I swear.
他们吃定我们了  我没有什么能做的了
They got us dead to rights. There's nothing more I can do.
扯淡  路易・利特从不向任何人妥协
Bullshit. Louis Litt does not roll over for anybody.
他没有妥协  唐娜
He didn't roll over, Donna.
我和本杰明仔细查看了一下
I went over it with Benjamin,
我们没办法把重叠部分降到百分之30以下
and we can't get the overlap under 30%.
我还让我自己的律师看了
I also ran it by my own attorney
他对路易给我们拿到的条件感到很震惊
and he was shocked at what Louis was able to get us.
所以你是说你想要接受吗
So you're telling me you want to take it?
我们想接受
We do.
但是没有你的话就没有真・唐娜
But The Donna wouldn't even exist without you,
我们是搭档  所以如果你不想接受的话
and we're partners, so if you don't want to,
我们就不接受
then we won't.
我得想想
I'm gonna need to think about it.
-那是什么  -自由铁路公司
- What's that? - Liberty Rail.
以前我就想给过你
I tried to give it to you once before.
但你不收
You wouldn't take it.
你说只有在没有附带条件的情况下你才会收下
You said it should come without strings.
现在我给你  没有附带条件
Well, here it is. No strings.
还是有条件的  你知道的
It's still got strings, and you know it.
你想让我帮迈克当上律师
You want me to let Mike in the Bar.
我的确想  但无论你帮不帮我都会给你这个
I do, but I'm giving you this whether you do that or not.
为什么
Why would you do that?
因为我希望如果我向你证明我可以改变
Because I'm hoping if I showed you I could change,
也许你能相信他也能改变
maybe you'd believe he could too.
你换他
You for him.
什么
What?
明天早上  我会问迈克
Tomorrow morning, I'm going to ask Mike
他在皮尔逊-斯佩克特工作时
if anyone knew he was a fraud
有没有人知道他是个骗子
while he was at Pearson Specter.
他要承认你知道  我就让他当律师
He admits you knew, I'll let him in the Bar.
如果我那么做  他们会把我踢出律师协会
I do that, they'll kick me out.
那就是"你换他"的含义
That's what "You for him" means.
你说过你愿意换他的
You said you'd do it for him once.
现在就是付诸行动的时候
This is your chance to put your money where your mouth is.
他不会答应
He won't go for it.
他想当律师都快想疯了
He wants to be a lawyer so bad he can taste it.
你可以强迫他
You can make him go for it.
记住
Just remember,
你不喜欢上次迟了的感觉
you didn't like being too late last time.
这次就不要再迟了
You're not too late this time.
太好了  你们俩都在  谢谢你们留下
Good. You're both here. Thanks for staying.
我们当然会留下  你信息上说很紧急
Of course we stayed. Your message said it was urgent.
怎么了
What's going on?
和解有什么问题吗
Is there a problem with the settlement?
并不是  我向奥利佛保证我会告诉你实情
No. I gave Oliver my word that I'd tell you the truth,
所以  我来告诉你实情了
so... I'm here to tell you the truth.
-什么实情  -我做了个交易
- Truth about what? - I made a deal.
等价交换  我们解决矿工的案子
A quid pro quo that we would handle the miners' case
以换取进入律师协会的机会
in exchange for the chance to be admitted to the Bar.
你在逗我吗
Are you goddamn kidding me?
我直截了当的问你有没有事瞒我
I asked you point blank if something was going on,
-你却在我面前撒谎  -纳森  我很抱歉
- and you lied to my face? - Nathan, I'm sorry.
但我只是想等
But I didn't want to tell you
事情真的能办再告诉你
until there was something to tell.
你是想等你自己全身而退之后再告诉我
You weren't going to tell me until you got away with it.
不  我不是
No, I wasn't.
事实证明  我无法全身而退了
But as it turns out, I'm not gonna get away with it,
但我还是要告诉你
and I'm telling you anyway.
-你被解雇了  -纳森  拜托...
- You're fired. - Nathan, please--
我一点也不在乎你接下来要说什么
I don't give a shit what's about to come out of your mouth.
清干净你的办公室
Clean out your office.
永远别再出现在这里
Never show your face around here again.
等等  别这么做
Wait. Don't do it.
你听到他说的话了吗
Did you hear what he said?
他说了谎  一而再再而三地说谎...
He lied. Not once, not twice--
我不在乎  因为我们需要他
I don't care, because we need him.
-我们不需要他  -索菲亚需要他
- We don't need him-- - Sophia needed him,
却只能由我代理  看看结果吧
and she got me, and look what happened.
是  纳森  他是做了坏事
Yeah, Nathan, that was some shady shit he pulled,
但如果你看不到他确实在乎委托人
but you gotta be blind if you can't see
那你一定是瞎了
that he actually cares.
而且在他来之前  我们从未获得过
And I don't remember us beating down a place
像极速数据处理公司案这样的胜利
like Velocity Data before he got here.
所以如果你无所谓的话  我想让他留下来
So if it's all the same to you, I'd like him to stay.
但我对这事不仅不无所谓  奥利弗
Well, it's not all the same to me, Oliver.
而且还有决定权
It's up to me.
像迈克一样对我有所隐瞒的人没有决定权
Not to the person that kept it from me as much as Mike did.
他没有想瞒你  纳森
He didn't keep it from you, Nathan.
他说如果我不告诉你  他就会告诉你
He said that if I didn't tell you, he would.
所以我来了
So here I am.
我知道我没有立场  但是
And I know I don't have a leg to stand on, but...
我想留下来
I'd like to stay.
周一早晨  你最好
Monday morning, you better start
拿出实际行动
putting your money where your mouth is
再为我们接个能赚五万美元的案子
and find us another $50,000 case.
-路易  你有空吗  -当然  哈维
- Louis, do you have a minute? - Sure, Harvey.
我不知道你对迈克
I don't know how much you know
听证会的情况了解多少
about what's going on with Mike's hearing.
我能看出你的表情意味着
Enough to know that look on your face
-听证会情况不太好  -是不太好
- means it's not going well. - It's not.
我可能有办法挽回局面
And I may have a way to change it,
但我想先和我的合伙人谈谈
but I wanted to run it by my partner first,
因为这可能意味着我要休息一段时间
because it may mean that I need a little time off.
"休息一段时间"是什么意思
What do you mean, "A little time off"?
意思是吉布斯跟我谈了个条件
I mean Gibbs offered me a deal.
迈克公开承认我知道他是个骗子
Mike goes on record admitting I knew he was a fraud,
她就投票让他进入律师协会
she'll vote to let him in the Bar.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
如果你这么做  就不只是休息一段时间了
You do that, it won't be a little time off.
你会被取消律师资格的
You'll get disbarred.
但那时候  迈克就是律师了
And by then, he'll be a lawyer.
我们可以主张他这么说只是为了安抚吉布斯
And we can argue that he said that just to appease Gibbs.
胡说  如果你这样做
Bullshit. You do this,
我们律所就会损失两个冠名合伙人
two out of three names on that wall will be gone,
我一个人无法维持律所运转
and I won't be able to keep this firm going.
如果你不行的话  我们也是帮了迈克的忙
And if you can't, we'll have done it for Mike.
赞恩会聘用你的
Zane will hire you.
我不想去赞恩的律所
I don't want to go to Zane's.
我想按照我们曾说过的那样
I want to do what we said we were gonna do
-一起重建这家律所  -路易  我欠他的
- and rebuild this place together. - Louis, I owe him.
那你欠我的呢
Well, what about what you owe me?
-你说过我们是合伙人  -我们是啊
- You said we were partners. - We are partners.
所以我才跟你说这些
Which is why I came to you with this.
不  你不是来征求我的同意的
No, you didn't come to ask my permission.
你是来通知我你要这么做的
You came to tell me that you were gonna do this.
如果就是如此呢
And what if I did?
那你就不只是个混蛋了
Then you're not just an asshole.
你还是个白痴  因为迈克・罗斯绝不可能
You're an idiot, because there's no way
同意用你的利益去交换他的
Mike Ross ever agrees to trading you for him.
-我会强迫他  -不  你强迫不了我
- Well, I'll make him agree. - No, you won't.
迈克
Mike.
哈维  不管她给你提供了什么条件
Harvey, whatever deal she's offering you,
我都不会接受的
I'm not gonna take it.
你都不知道条件是什么呢
You don't even know what it is.
我不管条件是什么
I don't care what it is.
如果要以把你从律师协会除名为代价
I'm not getting into the Bar
我是不会进入律师协会的
if it means getting you kicked out.
迈克  她想整的是我  一直如此
Mike, she wants me. She always has.
不  哈维  她想整我们俩
No, Harvey. She wants both of us.
除非把我们俩都整垮  否则她不会罢休的
And she's not going to stop until she gets both of us.
-你也不能确定  -不  我能
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
而且如果你不明白这一点
And if you don't get that,
那说明你是正中她下怀
then she's got you right where she wants you.
所以你明天就坐以待毙
So you're just gonna sit there tomorrow
让她夺走属于你的一切吗
and let her take everything away from you?
她没有夺走我的什么
She's not taking anything away.
她只是让事情保持了原样
She's keeping things exactly the way they are.
你是说在法律诊所工作
You mean working for that clinic.
哈维  我还能在法律诊所工作就很幸运了
Harvey, I'm lucky to still have a job at that clinic.
所以明天早晨  我会昂首挺胸地
So tomorrow morning, I'm gonna go in there
走进听证会
with my head held high.
但我不会
But what I'm not gonna do
让她夺走属于你的一切的
is let her strip you of everything that you are.
哈维  他说得对
Harvey, he's right.
放手吧
Let it go.
不管是什么事  唐娜...
Whatever it is, Donna...
哈维  我知道你现在处境困难
Harvey, I know you're in a rough place right now,
但是该来的迟早会来的
but whatever's gonna happen with Mike is gonna happen.
你已经尽力了
You've done everything you can.
而且我也实在等不下去了
And I'm tired of putting my wants on hold.
你想要什么
What is it?
你知道本杰明为我做的那个产品
You know about my product with Benjamin.
我知道
I do.
我们的软件和另一个公司的产品
Well, it turns out we have a 32.5% overlap
存在32.5%的重合部分
on our software with another company's.
他们拒绝让步  路易说
They refused to budge, and Louis said
他使劲了浑身解数让我们走到这一步
he pulled out every trick in the book to get us this.
-你们能让重合低于30%吗  -不行
- Can you get it under 30%? - No.
那就把钱收下吧
Then take the money.
我想要的不是钱
I don't want the money.
-唐娜  -我想要更多
- Donna-- - I want something more.
我从未出口承认过
And I've never said that out loud,
但我无法再假装这不是真的了
but I can't pretend that's not true anymore.
你说"更多"是什么意思
What do you mean "More"?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想我得把这一点弄清楚才行
I guess I'm gonna have to figure that out.
晚安  哈维
Good night, Harvey.
明天听证会见
I'll see you tomorrow at the hearing.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross,
我们准备好听取你的最终陈述了
we are prepared to hear your final statement.
在这之前  我还有最后一个问题
Before we do, I have one last question.
罗斯先生  你说你已改过自新
Mr. Ross, you say you're a changed man
还说自己重视事实
and you care about the truth.
但我想看看你是否能够说出事实
But I want to know if you're capable of telling the truth.
所以我要问你一个问题
So I'm going to ask you a question
我建议你小心斟酌自己的答案
and I suggest that you consider your answer very carefully,
因为在我看来
because as far as I'm concerned,
你的回答决定着
your answer will determine
你是否能够成为一名律师
whether or not you become a lawyer.
你在皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所
During your time at Pearson Specter Litt,
工作时  当时那里有人知道
did anyone there have knowledge of the fact
你是冒牌律师这个事实吗
that you were a fraud?
罗斯先生  律所里其他人知道吗
Mr. Ross. Did anyone else know?
我知道
I knew.
如果你非要拉一个人下马
And if you're looking for a scalp,
那就我来
you can have mine.
在我印象中  本次听证会无关于
But I was under the impression that this hearing
我过去那间律师  但无论怎样
was not about my old firm, but whether or not
罗斯先生都理应成为一名律师
Mr. Ross should be a lawyer.
依我看这是他应得的
I say he should.
你说什么并不重要
It doesn't matter what you say.
他已经找到人为他作证
He's already had someone testify for him.
我来这里不是为了谈论他
I'm not here to talk about him.
我来这里是为了谈论另一个人
I'm here to talk about someone else.
其他人和今天的听证会无关
Someone else has nothing to do with this--
我想听她说说
I'd like to hear this.
15年前  一个年轻女人
15 years ago, a young woman was arrested
因非法获取处方药而遭到逮捕
for illegally obtaining prescription drugs.
原来她患有慢性疼痛
Turns out she had chronic pain
但她不想从医学院退学
and didn't want to drop out of med school,
否则可能再也回不去了
possibly never to return.
因此她从自己实习的医院
So she stole a couple of prescription pads
偷了一些处方药
from the hospital where she was interning--
这一罪行可以被判处七年监禁
a crime with a mandatory sentence of seven years.
但当时检察官并未对她严惩
But instead of throwing the book at her,
而是选择了法外开恩
the prosecuting attorney showed mercy,
把控告判定为品行不端
had the charges knocked down to a misdemeanor,
建议缓刑  把记录封存
recommended probation, and sealed the records.
这是个感人的故事  但我不明白
That's a touching story, but I don't see
随便某律师和本次的品行考核有什么关系
what a random attorney has to do with these proceedings.
她说的不是随便某律师
She's not talking about a random attorney.
她说的是我
She's talking about me.
但仅仅因为我曾展现恻隐之心
But just because I showed compassion once
并不意味着现在他也值得我这么做
doesn't mean he deserves it now.
也许他是不值得
Maybe he doesn't.
但现在那个年轻女人成了一位急诊室医生
But that young woman is now an ER doctor.
她能救人性命
She saves lives.
因为你拯救了她的世界
And the world's a better place
她也让世界变得更好
because you saved hers.
谢谢你  皮尔逊女士  罗斯先生
Thank you, Ms. Pearson. Mr. Ross?
我认为我没有什么可多说的了
I don't think I can add anything to that.
我已阐明了所有理由
I've made my case.
决定权在你们手中
I leave the choice to you.
本次听证会结束
Then this hearing has concluded.
我们审议后会在今天之内给予你答复
We will deliberate and let you know our decision by day's end.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们现在要做些什么
So what do we do now?
他们说了会在今天之内给出答复
They said they would let us know by the end of the day.
那我们就等着吧
So we wait.
今天已经结束了  也就意味着...
Well, it is the end of the day, which means...
这并不意味着任何事  路易
It doesn't mean anything, Louis.
不管那边进行得怎么样
Whatever's going on in there,
赛德尔都会竭力争取的
Seidel's gonna fight like hell.
这也改变不了什么
It's not gonna make a difference.
安妮塔・吉布斯绝不会改变她的心意
She's never gonna change her mind.
-我认为她会的  -这是什么意思
- I think she will. - What do you mean?
我意思是那个故事并不只是个好故事
I mean that story wasn't any old story,
故事里的主角也不是一个女人
and that woman wasn't really a woman.
而是一个叫约瑟夫・奥尼尔的男人
It was a man named Joseph O'Neal.
他是沃特・山姆森的教子
And it was Walter Samson's godson.
-所以她确实找了关系  -是的
- So she did call in a favor. - Yeah, she did.
那我们得把她从委员会剔除
Then we need to get her kicked off that board.
不  哈维  我们不需要
No, Harvey. We don't.
因为我大老远飞过来
Because I didn't fly all the way down here
不是为了强迫她
to strong-arm that woman.
而且我知道太阳和风的故事
And I know the story of the wind and the sun.
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
她在说一则伊索寓言
She's talking about Aesop's fable.
故事是如果你想让人
Which basically says that if you want to get a man
脱掉衣服  吹冷风是没用的
to take off his coat, you don't blow it off.
必须给他温暖  才能让他自己脱掉
You make him feel warm, and he'll take it off on his own.
这不是解决办法  这是祈祷
That's not a strategy; it's a prayer.
路易  我已经承认了我知道迈克的事
Louis, I already admitted that I knew about Mike,
也唤起了她的同情心
and I reminded her of her own compassion.
这是最好的办法了
That's the best we're going to do.
你知道他们可能会吊销你律师执照的
You know they could disbar you for that.
在纽约  他们可能会
In New York, they might.
但在芝加哥  没人会关心的
In Chicago, nobody's gonna care.
谢谢你  杰西卡
Thank you, Jessica.
别谢我  谢哈维
Don't thank me. Thank Harvey.
是他叫我回来的
He's the one that called me.
是赛德尔打来的
It's Seidel.
你好
Hello.
我会转告他的
I'll tell him.
感谢来电
Thanks for calling.
你进了
You're in.
我的天呐  梦想成真了
Oh, my God. It happened.
我去开瓶香槟庆祝
I'm gonna go get us some champagne.
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
谢谢你赶来
Thank you for flying in.
我怎么会错过
I wouldn't miss this for the world.
半小时前你说要去洗手间
You said you had to go to the bathroom a half hour ago,
但却一直没回来喝香槟
but you never came back for your champagne.
我知道
I know.
路易  出什么事了
Louis, what's wrong?
你都没问过我塔拉那边怎么样了
You never asked me how it went with Tara,
毕竟我把迈克的事告诉她了
telling her about Mike.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
我最近一心扑在听证会的事上
I just got caught up with the hearing.
就是  我...
The thing is, I...
我告诉她了
I told her.
我们大吵一架
We got into a huge fight.
她说她要考虑一下
And she said she needed to think about
看能不能原谅我
whether or not she could forgive me.
-然后呢  -她刚打给我了
- And? - She just called
就在哈维跟我们说迈克的事的时候
when Harvey was giving us the news about Mike.
给我留了个十五秒的留言  但我不敢听
Left a 15-second voicemail. I'm afraid to listen to it.
路易
Louis...
要不就是要跟我说她再也不想见到我了
She's either gonna tell me that she never wants to see me again
要么就是要和好
or she wants to make up.
你想让我替你听吗
Do you want me to listen for you?
不想  但我想我听的时候你陪着我
No. But I'd like it if you stay with me while I do.
没问题
Of course.
这是什么
What's that?
我想给你一份礼物
I wanted to give you a present.
提前把你第一年的工资给你
Your first year's salary in advance.
-欢迎回来  -哈维  我已经不知道
- Welcome back. - Harvey, I'm running out of ways
该怎么告诉你我不想做企业律师了
to tell you I don't want to be a corporate lawyer.
在你给我答复之前
Before you answer,
先看看这张支票吧
you might want to take a look at this check.
-你这是贿赂  -我只是想套牢你
- You're trying to bribe me. - I'm trying to close you.
-我跟你说了...  -我知道
- I told you-- - Yeah, I get it.
你想做好事
You want to do good.
你要是真想做好事
Well, you really want to do good?
把这笔钱捐的一半去诊所
Donate half of this to the clinic.
够他们用一年了
You'll fund the place for a year.
你以为我是想做这种好事
Oh, so that's what you think I'm all about.
-就光捐钱  -不是
- Just giving money. - No.
但我觉得你该做的好事绝不止在那里工作
But I think you're about more than just working at that place.
-你自己也知道  -你在说什么
- And you know it. - What are you talking about?
我提出了个交易  为你  也为我
I'm offering you a deal. One for you, one for me.
你可以拯救花斑猫头鹰  阻止全球变暖
You can save the spotted owls, stop global warming,
受苦的女性想解救多少就解救多少
and help as many damsels in distress as you like.
好消息是  这些好事  你会在这里做
And the good news is, you'll be doing it from here.
你为什么觉得我会答应
What makes you think I'd take you up on that?
因为  迈克
Because here's the thing, Mike.
你想要在这里的  你自己也清楚
You wanna be here, and you know it.
不是的...
That's not true--
我看见了你脸上是怎样的神情
I saw the look on your face when you strong-armed Palmer
当你完胜帕默时  挑战赛德尔时
and you took on Seidel and every other talented attorney
打败每一个才华横溢的律师时
you've beaten over the years.
我之前就告诉过你
And I told you this once before.
这里是职业玩家的地盘
This is the major leagues.
这种成就感你在别的地方是找不到的
You don't get this feeling anywhere else.
现在你想要的我都能给你
And I'm offering you the best of both.
你为什么要给我比和平手势
Why are you giving me a peace sign?
-要双倍  -啥
- Double it. - What?
赞助诊所一年  不够
I don't wanna just fund the clinic for a year.
我要两年的赞助
I wanna fund it for two.
除了这个  还得有剩的钱
And while we're at it, I want some left over
给我和我未来的老婆买点好的
for a little something nice for me and the wife-to-be.
-就这样就够了吗  -差得远呢
- That's all it's gonna take? - Oh, not even close.
那是当然
I wouldn't have it any other way.
我想给诊所什么案子
Any case I want to bring the clinic on to,
-就给什么案子  -成交
- I can. - Done.
我想从诊所带什么人  就带什么人
Anyone I want to bring over from the clinic, I can.
路易说了不算  你说也不算
Louis doesn't get a say, you don't get a say,
-取消只要哈佛生的规定  -成交
- no Harvard rule. - Done.
还有一件事  但你不会喜欢的
And there's one more thing, and you're not gonna like it.
你别想要我的办公室
You are not getting my office.
我不仅要  还要告诉你为什么该给我
Oh, yes, I am. And I will tell you why.
-为什么  -因为她走了  哈维
- Why? - 'Cause she's gone, Harvey.
而且她不会再回来了
And she's not coming back.
是时候由你掌权了
It's time for you to take the reins.